- Hi everyone. And welcome.
So today we have a hamstring ball workout.
We're going to target the glutes,
hamstrings, abs, and core.
The timer is going to be on throughout,
45 seconds of work, 15 second rest.
Some exercises will be
performed for four sets,
others, two sets.
Simply follow along.
Stability balls come in various sizes.
And also depending on how
hard it is actually pumped up,
make this your own workout,
place your foot position
where is comfortable for you.
When you're doing the
hamstring ball roll outs,
as you can see here, try to control it.
Keep the hips up as high
as you can throughout.
Some of the exercises
you will also see me stabilising
with my elbows on the mat.
Others, I will lift my arms up
to make it that little
bit more challenging.
So of course it is your preference.
Play about.
This is not easy.
And especially
if you're not used to
stability ball workouts,
this is intense.
If you've never tried a
stability ball workout,
or you even go to the gym
and there is that
stability ball lying there
and you don't know what to do with it,
give this workout a go.
Your hamstrings will
be completely on fire.
Hamstring ball roll outs
have always been one of my
favourite hamstring exercises,
although it has been such a
long time since I've done it,
so I'm really looking
forward to doing this today.
Stability balls are always
a really good option
to have at home if you're
training from home.
And come in further videos,
I do expect to use the
stability ball a lot more.
Try not to get too frustrated
if you are new to this.
Take it slow.
You will progress quite quickly
if you keep practising .
We'll kick it off with the
hamstrings, moving on to abs,
and then we have a little
finisher back on those hamstrings.
Let's go.